It's nothing extraordinary.
Just the record of a girl
chosen by a peculiar disease.
In the human brain there are about
140 billion neurons and
10 times more cells,
which give orders to those neurons.
They're divided into 2 groups:
Central nervous system
and peripheral nervous system.
The central nervous system consists of the
brain, brain stem, cerebellum,
spinal cord and spinal column.
Allowing the body to
move freely and agilely,
are the cerebellum, the
brain stem, and the spine.
Mrs. Ikeuchi,
this is an image of your daughter's brain.
If you compare it with that of a normal brain,
you will see that the cerebellum is shriveled.
Your daughters disease,
is caused by deterioration of the cerebellum,
which causes the neurons there
to begin to disappear.
In other words, it's as if they
are beginning to break.
Break?
Initially there are no specific symptoms,
but you may begin to notice an instability walking.
A person will fall more often,
or have a difficulty calculating distances.
Perhaps having trouble writing clearly.
Why was I chosen to have this disease?
It will become difficult to speak.
Mom, what is the purpose of me living?
The symptoms start slowly,
but will undoubtedly progress.
Thinking of the future brings even more tears.
Mom, will I be able to get married?
[March 2005]
[Tofu ~ Ikeuchi Tofu Shop]
Morning!
Aya!
Good morning.
Aya, you were up late weren't you?
I think I was up till around 3am.
You barely got any sleep!
I was too nervous to sleep.
You can take the day off then.
No way!
But today is the admission test!
Her examination!
Do you think she'll pass if
she takes the day off?
Sometimes it's better to compromise...
Hey, this work isn't going to finish itself...
Right!
You brat!
Is that any way to speak to your parents?
Hiro, help me out.
Ok!
Like I said, take the day off.
Why don't you wait and see if we need you
or get a little bit more sleep, or...
If we're all here,
we can work without so much confusion.
I agree.
But that...
Eh?
Where's Ako?
Hey, how long do you plan to stay in bed?
Alright, time to wake up! We have work to do!
Be quiet!
It's morning Ako! It's time to get up, it's morning.
You're so annoying!
I told you to wake up!
Full body attack!
Morning after morning!
This is abuse, you know? Abuse!
If you don't work you can't eat!
Don't complain!
I'm not complaining.
It's a legitimate protest!
-- You should at least pay me properly!
-- Rika, you're such a sweet girl.
You'd never bring up money, right?
I work 8 hours a day and
all I get is 3000 yen!
The norm is 800 yen per hour!
It's ridiculous!
Don't start.
Whatever.
My pay is 1000 yen...
I work 30 hours per month... So...
Hiroki, you can't even figure that out?
I'm horrible at multiplication!
It's a ratio!
Eh?
Hiroki, you're the Ikeuchi family heir!
If you can't do such a simple calculation,
how can you handle a business?
Aya, I need some tofu please.
Yes!
What are you doing?
Sorry!
What a waste!
Damn, she dropped it!
Let's not use that word today.
Let's not.
Damn, I dropped it.
Damn! I said it!
-- See you later
-- See you later!
Wait! Wait I said!
Do your best!
Aya wait! You forgot something!
Your ID for the exam!
You're so careless...
Just like someone else I know!
Well, I'm off!
Wait, wait a minute!
Take this with you.
Thank you!
[Talisman for success in business]
Success in business?
Like father, like daughter!
They're all the same. Take it with you.
I'll see you later!
Aya, good luck!
Good luck!
[1 Liter of Tears]
This program is offered by: Life Card,
P & G,
DoCoMo Group,
Shiseido,
Kagome
and Kobayashi Pharmaceutical.
[Entrance Exam Hall ~ Mewadai Higashi High]
What's Aya doing?
Please go get ready for the test!
I'm sorry Aya!
What am I going to do?
I'll never make it in time!
I guess I've delayed long enough.
It hurts!
You've gotta be kidding!
Excuse me.
Don't worry about it.
Please begin!
Get on!
Well, excuse me then.
Good news. You two can do the examination here.
Is that okay?
However, in fairness to the other students,
you'll still only have 1 hour to finish.
Okay?
Yes! Thank you!
Well, actually... I just...
It's very admirable of you
to have chosen to help someone.
It's not like that.
Asahina school #3, freshman 2114.
-- Ikeuchi Aya, right?
-- Yes!
Kasagura middle school,
freshman 1093. Asou Haruto?
Yes.
Today is Aya's entrance exam, right?
Yes, it is.
For Meiwadai Higashi.
Eh? Higashi?
That's a very good high school!
Oh, it's not that big a deal.
-- So... that leaves you with 180 yen.
-- Shouldn't it be 350 yen?
No wonder they call this place expensive.
She had the baby? Congratulations!
Now you have to keep yourself
healthy for the good of your niece.
Mrs. Ikeuchi, you have a call from Kaede clinic.
I'll call them back.
I just wrote up a very filling low
calorie recipe I think you'd like.
I could bring it over later.
Oh, Mrs. Ikeuchi!
I'll see you then!
My blood pressure is even higher than
yesterday. What should I do?
Can you wait just one moment,
Mrs. Hashimoto?
Mrs. Ikeuchi, can you stop by Mr. Yamada's later?
He says he won't accept anyone else.
Okay. Tell him I'll be there this afternoon.
Mrs. Ikeuchi, I brought these for you.
I picked them from my garden just this morning.
Thank you, you're always so kind.
Honestly. Falling asleep
on the bus before our exam...
Do you have some kind of grudge
against this place or what?
Didn't you say you weren't going
to take the first test?
I didn't plan to.
Are you serious?
Hey Aya, when we get to high school
why don't you buy a cel phone?
I think you're the only one who doesn't have one.
If you'd had a phone this morning
you could have called me.
Ah!
Aya!
Um...
Thank you for this morning!
Thanks to you...
It's all your fault I had to take the test.
Eh?
Who is she?
I don't know.
Haruto!
You rode a bike with a boy?
Were you late?
Who is this guy?
Where is he from?
She's fine, isn't she?
He just helped her get there on time.
Is he a boy you can't even tell us about?
But I only managed to finish about half the test.
Can I have more?
Rika eat your carrots.
Isn't anyone listening to me?
Dad you spit everywhere, that's disgusting!
How dare call your parents disgusting!
Disgusting is disgusting!
We should thank this guy for giving you a ride.
What? Thank him?
What are you thinking?
How can you allow a girl her age
to get on a bike with a boy?
It is not a question of age, right?
The problem is her cycling with a boy.
Well, look...
I hope you both passed.
What am I gonna do if I didn't?
It'll be fine.
Damn, it fell...
Oh... damn, it...
I mean, it just slipped out!
-- My number! My number!
-- Mine too!
Thank God! We did it!
Ikeuchi!
Kawamoto.
You both got in. Congratulations!
Thank you!
They were on my basketball
team in middle school.
This is Takeda, from my new team.
It's nice to meet you!
Our pleasure.
Ikeuchi, you're going to keep playing
in high school, right?
We will.
I'm glad.
Our team is pretty strict, so make
sure you prepare yourselves.
Of course.
Well then, I'll see you there.
He said "I'm glad."
Cut it out.
You've had a crush on him since we were 11...
Why not tell him?
No way! That's impossible!
Then should I tell him for you?
No! Don't you dare!
Come on, It's irritating watching you wait around.
Don't be angry.
I'm not angry, but...
By the way, the guy who helped
you on the day of the test...
did he get in?
[Closed in celebration of exams.
Will reopen as usual tomorrow.
-Ikeuchi Tofu Shop.]
Congratulations!
Thank you!
Well done!
-- As expected of my daughter.
-- Dad, you didn't go to Higashi.
Why do you always say such unnecessary things?
Shall we eat?
Bon appetit!
Thank you for the food.
-- What is it?
-- Aya, congratulations!
Thank you!
Aya, this is for you.
Eh? Really?
Thank you!
Don't bother saying thank you.
There's no way you're
happy to get that.
I am!
It's Hiro's treasure, right?
-- Just like an honor student.
-- Stop it already.
What are you giving her, Ako?
I can't give her anything.
I can't even buy the clothes I want.
Can I have some more?
Here.
Anyways,
you guys just keep going
on about Higashi.
It's stupid.
This is a gift from your father.
Ta-dan!
Thanks Dad!
I made it myself.
-- Really?
-- He's lying!
Your father used to work at a watch shop.
He says that's where
he learned how to make it.
I have something special for Ako too.
Ta-dan!
What is that?
It's cute, isn't it?
I also worked in a tailoring.
You've done so many things, Dad.
That just means nothing you did lasted long.
What did you say?
I only changed jobs
to find what suited me best.
-- You make it sound so beautiful, eh?
-- But after
so many different jobs he decided
to manage this store
and make tofu. Isn't that great?
I agree!
Come on, let's see how it looks!
What?
Oh, it looks great on you!
Like I'd ever wear something
so out of fashion!
Out of fashion?
-- Just wear it at home then.
-- In the house?
-- Or to sleep.
-- To sleep?
Or under a sweater.
Under a sweater?
Is it that bad?
Hey Mom!
Since we're celebrating
my admission to school
we should let dad have some beer!
Please, just one bottle!
I guess it can't be helped.
Really?
Of course!
I'll get it.
I'm so happy!
Here, Dad.
Thank you!
My first beer in so long,
all thanks to Aya.
How wonderful!
What are you doing?
Sorry!
My first beer after so long...
That was careless of me!
Sorry!
Don't worry.
On no! I used this to clean it.
Ako's shirt...
What are you doing with the lights off?
Sorry I'm late, we had a
last minute meeting.
Congratulations on the exam.
Thank you.
Now you can follow in
my and Keisuke's footsteps.
You should be a little more happy.
You're such a strange boy.
You know, he didn't even go to see the results.
No?
His professor contacted us to let us know.
Worried you wouldn't get in?
Well, let's go get ready for dinner.
I must be tired.
[Admission Ceremony]
Ta-dan!
How's it look?
You look great!
-- Really?
-- It looks great!
I want to wear it too!
Then all of us have to go to
the same high school.
No thanks.
With my grades,
I could never get into Higashi.
Yes you could!
I don't want to anyways.
Thank you for the food.
I'm sorry we can't go to the ceremony.
It's okay, you have work to do.
It can't be helped.
Alright, I'm ready!
-- Why are you dressed like that?
-- For the admission ceremony, of course.
What about the shop?
We'll reopen it this afternoon.
What kind of tofu shop
is only open in the afternoon?
But...
Hey dad, let's take a picture.
Okay. Here we go.
Now smile!
Change poses. Beautiful!
Now come over here!
-- Mom, you come too.
-- Yes, yes!
Hey, you've lose weight, haven't you?
You think?
You aren't on some strange diet, are you?
Of course not.
You have to be sure to take good care of yourself.
I know.
Let's take another. Come on everyone.
I'll pass.
No, no.  Join us.
Wait a minute... Okay, here we go.
Make room for me. Smile!
Alright.
See you later.
Be careful.
That's why I said be careful.
[Meiwadai Higashi High School
2005 Admission Ceremony]
I'm your supervisor Nishino.
I'll be your English professor,
and an assistant for
the female basketball team.
I hope that for this year...
Everyone here seems so intelligent, don't they?
It's going to be hard to keep up!
I'll start by taking roll.
Asou Haruto.
Asou?
Asou Haruto?
-- Onda!
-- Yes!
You and Asou went to the same school, right?
Have you heard anything?
No.
You're late Haruto!
It's the day of the ceremony and
you show up late?
Excuse me.
While I was on my way, I saw
a girl fall and hurt herself.
I couldn't just leave her, so
I brought her to hospital.
You never fail to find trouble, do you?
Well then, sit down.
That's the guy from the day of the test, right?
Kouhei Onda.
Akihiro Okada.
Hey, was that true?
No.
I knew it!
What a strange guy.
Now, it's time to decide
the class representatives.
Would anyone like to volunteer?
Well then, are there any suggestions?
Okay, then for the first semester,
the task will belong to
the first people in the registry.
-- For the boys, Asou.
-- What, are you kidding?
For the girls, Ikeuchi.
Are these two okay?
Well, then please do a good job.
-- Yes!
-- What a pain!
Representatives, please come to the front!
I think you've already been informed
of the singing contest this June.
It's one of the traditions of Higashi.
So that new students can cooperate
and be united as a class.
First of all we must decide on a
music director and conductor.
Representatives, please proceed with the debate.
Um...
Well, first of all, we should choose
an orchestra director.
I think the class representatives should do it.
In that case, you go ahead!
Eh?
We'll vote.
So, for the director...
What was your name, again?
Ikeuchi.
Is anyone opposed to Ikeuchi?
Then it's decided.
-- Wait...
-- Now we have to think of a song.
I think that should be
decided by our representatives too.
You were chosen as a class representative?
That's amazing!
As expected of my daughter!
Dad, you weren't class representative, were you?
Well, no.
Of course.
But the other representative is useless!
Oh, it's the guy who gave me a
ride the day of the test.
The one with the bike?
You are in the same class?
You should bring him over sometime.
Well, I guess it can't be helped.
We'll treat him to some tofu!
-- But weren't you against him the other day?
-- If it weren't for him
Aya wouldn't have gotten into Higashi.
He kind of forced me to accept the
role of director of orchestra.
What? What? What?
Really?
My daughter, leading a team
in front of an audience?
I want to come and see!
Rika too!
Me too!
Aya, you're so clumsy!
I really am! Even you're better than me.
A competitive singing group, eh?
Hospital?
I'm just a little bit worried.
You've been dropping things
a lot lately, right?
You've been falling down more often too...
It's probably just because I'm tired.
But still...
Come on mom, don't scare me!
It's frightening to have a mother in
health care say things like that!
I'm not trying to scare you, but...
Well if you're that worried,
I'll make a trip to the hospital for your sake.
Really? Let's do that.
That way I won't have to worry.
I'm fine. I'm only 15.
I'm done in the bathroom.
Aya, go take a bath.
Ok.
-- Um... You're Tomita, right?
-- What is it?
I was hoping you'd help me
with the singing competition?
Have someone else do it.
You're the only one in our
class who can play the piano.
The class representatives should do it.
Your social status will go up if one of you
directs and the other plays the piano.
First year students, welcome!
I'm your manager, Nishino.
I'm Kaori Honda, the team leader.
It's nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you!
First of all, let's see what you can do.
Yes!
Line up one at a time, like your classmates.
Yes.
The third year girls will demonstrate first.
Aya, look.
Kawamoto's so cool, isn't he?
Um... we're in the same class, right?
I'm Matsumura Saki.
Ah! The girl with glasses.
This is my first time playing basketball.
-- Next.
-- Yes!
Why the biology club?
If you want to get girls,
shouldn't you try music or soccer?
I'm not trying to get girls.
What about joining...
The biology club.
Why?
I hear the president is beautiful.
Really?
You're from our class.
Yes. My name is Nakahara Keita.
Where's the president?
-- You want to join?
-- Yes!
I'm Yoshikawa, the president.
Welcome to the biology club.
Why didn't you wake me?
I tried to, over and over!
No way!
I did.
You didn't want to get up.
Be sure to eat before you go.
I'll be fine.
You're taking it too lightly.
When your sister got into her second year...
I'm not like her. I can't do anything right.
Why do you always say that!
Who cares? You're the good girl.
If only you weren't around...!
Ako, wait!
What was that about?
Dad, I'm leaving.
See you later.
Be careful!
Aya?
Hey, Shioka!
Aya, Aya...
What happened?
Are you okay?
Shioka!
Calm down. Are you okay?
Call an ambulance!
I'll bring her to the hospital.
I'll go too.
Let me see your towel!
Press this against it.
Can you stand up?
Are you okay?
You'll be alright.
Get in.
You have a delivery to make, right dear?
If you come with us, you won't make it in time.
But...
Take care of Rika.
I'll call you in a bit.
I'll leave it up to you then.
Drive carefully!
Can you get out?
Oh, good morning.
What a surprise!
I was asked to bring this here.
Professor Asou.
Your son is here.
Thank you.
It's the speech for today's meeting.
It was careless of me to forget it.
Can you still get to school on time?
Yes. I'll see you later.
Haruto...
Thank you, you really helped me out.
Asou?
What did you do to your face?
I fell.
You fall an awful lot, don't you?
What about you? Are you sick?
They say... I don't have much time left.
Apparently it progresses rapidly...
You can't mean...
I'm kidding.
Eh?
I have athlete's foot.
That's disgusting.
I'm kidding.
Eh?
Hi.
Someone you know?
She's my ex.
Eh? She's so much older than you are.
-- I'm kidding.
-- Eh?
I hear you got into Higashi.
Congratulations.
My father is one of the doctors who work here.
You're lying again, right?
Right. You figured it out.
There are no fractures.
It should heal in about a week.
Doctor,
There's something that's been bothering me...
Usually when a person falls,
they'll put their hands out to stop it, right?
Yes.
My daughter's hands weren't scratched at all.
She landed directly on her face.
That's strange, isn't it?
Also,
she's been dropping things a lot lately,
and has been having trouble using chopsticks.
[Dr. Hiroshi Mizuno]
I'll see you later.
Think of a song for the competition, ok?
You decide.
Anything is fine.
No. There has to be something...
Do we want a cheerful song?
One with a specific theme?
It doesn't matter.
I won't like anything.
Eh?
I'm telling you, anything is fine.
I won't complain.
Humans are greedy, don't you think?
In what sense?
Plants and animals are content with the
world from the time they're born.
Humans are the only creature
that try to force life to continue.
He really is strange...
Aya!
Mom?
Before we go home, let's have them do a check up.
Check up?
Why isn't she calling?
I'm Mizuno, the neurologist.
Thank you for taking care of me.
When did you first start having problems walking?
About a month ago I think,
but I believe it's just because
I haven't gotten enough sleep.
What about falling down?
The first time was the day of my entry test.
But it was because I was in a hurry.
Have you ever found it difficult to speak?
A little more quickly.
Hello?
I... Well...
How's Aya?
How bad is the wound?
Will it heal?
It won't scar, will it?
No, she'll be fine.
They said it should heal without any problems.
Really?  Oh, good!
Thank God!
-- Anyways... About Aya...
-- Oh, you know...
I couldn't relax all day.
I was afraid she'd have a scar on her face.
That would have been so heart breaking for her.
You don't have to worry about that, but...
Really? Oh good, I'm so glad.
Thanks Shioka.
Anyways... We'll be home soon.
Okay, be careful.  I'll see you then.
Excuse us.
We'll let you know the results in a few days.
Thank you.
Um...
Is something wrong with me, doctor?
If you notice anything unusual in
your physical behavior,
I'd like you to write it down for me.
Okay.
Don't over think it.
Just look at it as a diary.
A diary?
How could you trip and
hurt your chin that badly?
I know. I'm so clumsy.
Can I come in?
Dad?
How's your chin?
Does it hurt?
A little.
I can't believe it kept me
from going to school though.
Most people would be happy to skip school.
That's true! We're alike after all, eh?
Shut up!
Anyways,
you should get some rest.
Eh?
Studying is important of course,
but there are more important things.
The important thing is to know your limits.
Limits?
Not really limits.
You just need to find a good balance.
I see.
I guess you're right.
Yes.
Since Professor Tanaka is out today,
use this time for self study.
Representatives, have you chosen
a song for the competition?
I'm sorry, we haven't yet.
You have 1 week to decide.
That's all for now.
I thought it was up to Ikeuchi to decide.
Well, but...
Anything is fine.
Why doesn't everyone write down a
song they like, and give it to me?
Then we can choose from that list.
Which one is the dog?
Yes, good job!
Next, we'll need to measure his
height and weight.
Okay.
That way, please.
Mrs. Ikeuchi, you have a phone call.
Hello, this is Mrs. Ikeuchi.
This is Dr. Mizuno of the neurology
department at University Clinic Jonan.
The results are ready.
Yes?
Could I please have you come to the
hospital as soon as possible?
If you could, I'd like you to bring
your husband as well.
You're saying that...
this isn't a matter that can be
discussed over the phone?
It would be better for us to meet here.
I'll be waiting.
Um...
About the song for the singing contest...
You have an idea?
It's not that.
Um...
Since we have our first hour free,
why don't we discuss it together?
Um, since we're all a part of this contest...
How should I put this...
I think we should all cooperate.
Where's your husband?
I came alone.
It's fine.
I work in health care,
and I used to be a nurse.
More than anything else,
I'm her mother.
Why don't we all propose our favorite songs?
Oh, give me a break.
I don't like debates.
The competition is just a waste of time anyways.
We don't have much time before the next test.
I want to study.
We'll still have plenty of time
for that, won't we?
I believe that the illness your
daughter is suffering from is
spinocerebellar degeneration.
Spinocerebellar degeneration?
I will run some more tests to be sure,
but I'm fairly sure that there's no mistake.
My father runs a tofu shop.
Originally, when he inherited the shop from
my grandfather, he was opposed to the idea,
so he tried other jobs.
At first he worked for City Hall,
but desk work just didn't suit him.
So he left City Hall and
tried several other jobs.
He grew tired of everything quickly
and never stayed any place very long
but he was able to make me a watch,
and this old fashioned T-shirt,
and his cooking is the be....
What are you talking about?
I don't understand the point of this.
Um...
What I'm trying to say is...
Even though he constantly strayed
from the normal path
nothing he did was meaningless.
In the end, following his own path
led to his decision to run the shop.
So, isn't it okay to take a different path every once in awhile?
The symptoms start slowly,
but will undoubtedly progress.
Although nerve damage will stop her
from being able to move freely
there will be no damage to the brain.
Even though she'll want to move,
she won't be able to.
When she wants to speak,
She will be fully aware of these limitations.
It's an extraordinarily cruel disease.
It can be cured, right?
Instead of rushing forward, he immersed
himself in a variety of things.
Shouldn't the class representative...
It can be cured, right?
As far as I know,
nobody has ever recovered from it.
I don't think it's that bad
for people to waste a little time.
After all, we still have plenty of time left.
If I were a flower, I would be the bud.
I want to treasure the early days of
my youth with no regrets.
[Kitou Aya at age 15]
Kanashimi no mukou wo kishi ni
[On the coast across from sadness]
Hohoemi ga aru toiu yo
[they say there lies is a smile]
Tadoritsuku sono saki ni wa
[When we get there]
Nani ga bokura wo matteru
[Something will be waiting for us]
Nigeru tame ja naku
[We must not run away]
Yume ou tame ni
[In order to chase our dreams]
Tabi ni deta hazu sa
[We have to go back]
Tooi natsu no ano hi
[to that distant summer day]
Ashita sae mieta nara
[If I could just see tomorrow]
Tameiki mo nai kedo
[I wouldn't breathe a sigh]
Nagare ni sakarau fune no you ni
[Like a ship rows against a storm]
Ima wa mae e susume
[I must continue to move forward]
Amakumo ga kireta nara
[When the rain clouds disappear]
Nureta michi kagayaku
[the wet roads glisten]
Yami dake ga oshiete kureru
[Only in darkness will you see]
Tsuyoi tsuyoi hikari
[The bright, bright light]
Tsuyoku mae e susume
[That guides us forward]
[There are various types of spinocerebellar degeneration.
The progression of the disease
differs from person to person.
This drama is based on a true story
and was produced with the help of a doctor.
All names have been changed.]
[In the next episode]
What stupid doctor told you this?
She can be cured, right?
There is no cure.
Why Aya?
It's unfortunate, but it's the truth.
Mom, what disease do I have?